本集字幕由擦枪字幕组原创译制
翻译：甘八
翻译：pretender
翻译：柠檬
校对：柠檬
片源：耐卡
马哈斯波特 缅因州
啊啊 啊 啊 啊
Ah-ah, ah, ah, ah
我愿为你而死
I would die for you
我的死亡是为了
I've been dying just to
感受你在我左右
Feel you by my side
来感觉你属于我
To know that you're mine
我愿为你而死
I would die for you.
惠蒂尔 加利福尼亚州
萨姆
-Sam? -Hmm?
聊两句
A quick word?
你用了三个小时
Three hours all in?
我只用了俩小时
I did it in two.
她送过来时一团糟
She was in bad shape when she came in.
你做得很好
Good work.
哦 我们到底要聊些什么
Oh, are we having a moment?
你刚来的时候 我以为你干不了一个星期
When you first started here, I didn't think you'd last a week.
是啊 没有了我你可怎么办啊
Yeah, and now, what would you do without me?
虽然你付我的薪水远远不够
-Yeah. -I mean, you don't pay me nearly enough,
但算你走运 我做这一行是因为热爱
but, um, you're lucky I do it for the love of the game.
我能从你工作中看得到
I can see that... in the work.
你是真的在乎
You actually care.
我认为值得给你加个薪
I think that deserves a raise.
呃 谢谢您
Um, uh, thank you.
我确实在乎
Yeah. I-I do care.
我认为我们的工作很特别
I-I believe what we do here is very special.
继续保持这个势头 萨姆
Keep your head in the game, Sam.
你在这里前途无量
You've got a bright future here.
谢谢
-Thank you.
杰西
Jesse?
Jesse?!
嗨 你回来了
Hey, you.
-嗨 -我昨晚好想你
-Hi. -Missed you last night.
抱歉 真希望你当时也在场
I'm sorry. I wish you could've seen it.
那家人对我说了谢谢 天啊 太感人了
The family thanked me. God, it was so emotional.
就连亨德森也承认我干的好
Even Henderson had to admit that I did a great job, and then...
他还给我加薪了
-...he offered me a raise. -Hmm.
听起来 你今天过得不错
It sounds like you had a good day.
是啊
Mm-hmm.
今晚给我好好讲讲
You'll have to tell me all about it tonight.
- 我得走了 开庭要迟到了 -别嘛
-I got to go. I'm late for court. -No.
来吧 大律师
Come on, Counselor.
晚几分钟也没关系的
You can be a couple minutes late.
有时候打破常规也会很有趣
Mm, sometimes it's fun to go off script.
谁知道冥冥之中藏着什么惊喜
Maybe the universe will surprise you.
还有人指望着我呢
I've got people depending on me.
我得为受害者报仇 把罪犯绳之以法
Victims to avenge, criminals to put away.
行吧 去拯救世界吧
Okay, well, go save the world or whatever.
不如你去洗个热水澡
Why don't you... go take a nice hot bath
用点我给你买高级薰衣草精油
with some of that fancy lavender oil I got you?
我下班前已经洗过两次了 不过
Showered twice before I left work, but...
估计是我鼻窦太敏感
Maybe it's just my, uh, extra sensitive sinuses,
但那股甲醛味真的很冲
but that formaldehyde smell is really something.
拜
-Bye.
待会儿见 宝贝
See you later, babe.
你身上可能是有培根和死亡的味道
Look, you probably smelled like bacon and death.
-这会让人很没性致 -不
-Nobody wants to fuck that. -No, I...
就是心里觉得怪怪的
-It all just felt kind of weird.
是有点怪 如果男人拒绝上床
Yeah, it's weird. If a guy turns down sex,
-感情肯定是出了严重问题 -说不好
-something is seriously wrong. -SAM: Oh, I don't know.
就算我们真的上床了 也感觉
Even when we do have sex, it's just like...
缺了点什么
something's... missing.
总之有点不对劲
It's just something off.
我们两个就像朝不同方向
It's-it's like we're on separate tracks,
前进的两列列车
heading in different directions.
而且 他不会明说 但我知道
And, like, he won't exactly say it, but I know
他不喜欢我在殡仪馆工作
he doesn't like me working at the funeral home.
有时我都怀疑 他是不是真的理解我
And sometimes I just wonder if he even gets me at all.
姑娘 你可是会跟死人说话的
Girl, you talk to dead people, literally.
经营感情意味着妥协
-Relationships are about compromise.
没有十全十美的事儿
Nothing's perfect.
比如 你最近为杰西做了什么
Like, what have you done for Jesse lately?
我
I, uh...
我有时会洗碗
I do the dishes. Sometimes.
想起来时会洗洗衣服
Laundry. When I remember.
我前几天开了十分钟的车
I drove ten minutes out of the way
买了他最爱吃的冰淇淋
the other day to get his favorite ice cream.
-哇哦 -很可以
-DANI: Wow. -Cool.
如果杰西直接让你选
If Jesse asked you, point blank,
不换工作 就换我
Either the job's got to go, or I do,
你会怎么选
which would you pick?
你犹豫了 杰西真可怜
You hesitated. Poor Jesse.
不 不 只不过
No, no. It's just, it's...
这很复杂
It's complicated.
这有什么复杂的
What am I missing?
我是真的很喜欢自己的工作
I really love my job.
我做得也很优秀
And I'm good at it.
而且 你每天都能从逝者身上
And, uh, the deceased teach you
学到些新东西
something new every day.
如何学
How?
他们都死了
They're dead.
看 秘密就在这
See, that's the secret.
人在死后才是最有意思的
People are the most interesting right after death.
有一次 有个女的突然开始呻吟
One time, this woman started moaning.
她还活着吧
Was she still alive?
死得很彻底
Totally dead.
在尸体分解过程中 气体会积聚在―起
Gases-- they can build up during decomposition,
越积越多时 会从嘴中排出
and when they try to escape, sometimes it hits
有时气流会撞击到声带
vocal cords on the way out of the mouth.
有时血液会向下面聚集
Sometimes the blood rushes all the way down.
还会导致死者勃起
A decedent will come in with a boner.
好恶心 萨姆
- Ew! Sam.
人类的身体千奇百怪
SAM: The human body is insane.
其内部原理 我们只了解到了
And we only understand a small blip of what's actually
很小一部分 所以总是会有
happening inside, so there's always
有新发现
something new to discover.
但除此之外
But, okay, beyond that,
我 我能帮助到别人
I... I help people.
把他们的亲人朋友带回他们身边
I get to bring their loved ones back to them,
哪怕就一小会儿
just for a little while.
我做的事 很重要
What I do is... it's important.
你只要谈起死人 这股兴奋劲
You just got more excited talking about dead people
远远超过谈杰西的时候
than you've ever been talking about Jesse.
也许他不是问题所在
Maybe he's not the problem.
我天 你是出什么事了
SAM: Yikes. What happened to you?
雷金纳德·葛洛夫 55岁
Reginald Glover, 55 years old.
死因 头部中枪
Cause of death: gunshot wound to the head.
不开玩笑了
No kidding.
嗨 葛洛夫先生 我是萨姆
Hi, Mr. Glover. I'm Sam.
我今天负责照顾你
I'll be taking care of you today.
这上面说 你家人选择了开放式棺材
Looks like your family wants you to have an open casket,
所以 咱俩得―起把你收抬的齐齐整整
so, I'm gonna need you to work with me
迎接你生命中最重要的一天
so we can make you look presentable for your big day.
我看到你有六个孩子 真不错
I see you had six kids. Nice.
他们给你选择了红木棺材
Looks like they got you the mahogany casket.
这是我们最贵的一款
That's our most expensive one.
你―定是个好爸爸
You must've been a good dad.
现在
And now...
我天啊 你好 抱歉
Uh, whoa. Hi. Um, sorry.
你来这里干什么 这里谢绝入内
What-what are you doing here? This is a restricted area.
请你马上出去
Can you get out?
我是查理 新来的掘墓移尸官
I'm Charlie, the new grave digger and death removal tech.
我没想故意吓到你
Didn't mean to freak you out.
请问我应该把她放在哪儿
Just tell me where to leave her.
那边就行
Um, just over there.
我这边完事后会去照顾她
I'll-I'll get to her when I wrap up.
嘿 你刚才对死者说了什么
Hey, what did you say down there to the decedent?
就感谢了她一下
I just thanked her.
感谢她什么
Thanked her for what?
是我们的悄悄话
It's kind of private.
抱歉 我刚才冲你发脾气
Well, I'm-I'm sorry I blew up on you.
只不过 你是不能来下面的
It's just, you weren't supposed to be down there.
我知道了 不会有下次了
I hear you. Won't happen again.
我叫萨姆
I'm Sam.
很高兴认识你 萨姆
Nice to meet you, Sam.
所以你这身打扮又是西装又是帽子
So, um, what's up with the... the suit, the hat,
开一辆如此拉风的车
-pimped-out ride?
大多数移尸官不会
Most, um, body removal techs don't
搞得这么浮夸和隆重
roll up with all that pomp and circumstance.
我觉得每个人都值得被体面的送走
I think all of us deserve to be sent off in style.
你想啊 谁愿意坐在起亚里迎接来世呢
I mean, who wants to ride into the afterlife in a Kia Sorento?
有道理
Fair enough.
我感谢逝者允许
I thanked the decedent for allowing me
我护送她来见你
to escort her to you.
你是认真的吗
Seriously?
加入某人的死亡之旅是一种荣誉
It's an honor to be a part of someone's death journey.
在古埃及 只有专门的牧师
You know, in ancient Egypt, only specialized priests,
被神亲手选中的人 才有资格处理逝者
those handpicked by the gods, were trusted to handle the dead.
他们会花70天将尸体荣装端整
They'd spend up to 70 days on one body,
送他进入来世
getting it ready for the afterlife.
这一点我确实有耳闻
I did know that.
你看起来真美
You look incredible.
这是要干嘛
What's all this?
只是想为我爱的人盛装打扮
Just wanted to look nice for my guy.
我在想 或许我们可以
Thought maybe we could go...
出去吃晚餐
out to dinner?
我更想呆家里
I think I'd rather stay in.
所以 你相信死后的世界吗
So, you believe in the afterlife?
不我认为印度教有其道理
No. I think the Hindus have it right.
转世轮回
Reincarnation, samsara.
如果你能转世再生
You come back as any living thing,
你想做个什么
what would you come back as?
我不想再有来生了
I wouldn't want to come back.
我相信人就活―辈子 一锤定音
Um, I'm Team One Life, one and done.
是吗
-Oh. -Mm-hmm.
所以你会按照西藏的习俗
So you'd go out like the Tibetans?
把尸体肢解 洒落在山上
Chop up your body, scatter the pieces
供奉秃鹰
on the mountain for the vultures.
然后 尘归尘 土归土 回到大自然
You'd just return to the earth and all that jazz?
天葬感觉又繁琐又可怕
A sky burial seems unnecessarily gruesome.
不过我可以接受亚马逊人的做法
But, uh, I could get down with how the Amazons do it.
火葬
Cremation,
然后把骨灰拌到汤里 喂给整个部落
then stirring your ashes into soup for the whole tribe.
这也是一种回馈社区的方式
Plus, you'd be giving back to the community.
1500年前的中国 一个女人将自己活埋
CHARLIE: 1,500 years ago in China, a woman buried herself
为他丈夫殉葬 以求生生世世在一起
alive with her dead husband so they could achieve immortality.
这就有点狗血了
That's a bit dramatic.
这才是真爱
That's true love.
纳尔逊勋爵的尸体
SAM: Lord Nelson's body
被泡在一桶白兰地里运回家
was shipped home in a cask of brandy.
在航行中 水手们还偷喝了—小口
The sailors even stole sips along the voyage.
你会偷喝吗
Would you steal a sip?
当然 为什么不呢
Sure. Why not?
实践出真知
Can't learn anything if you don't try everything.
我本身已经挺爱冒险了 不过
I'm pretty adventurous, but, um,
但对尸体泡酒还是接受不了
think I'd draw the line at Dead Nelson juice.
你吃过最冒险的东西是什么
What's the most adventurous thing you've ever eaten?
好久都没这种尝试了
It's been a minute. Um...
我男友不太喜欢尝试新事物
My boyfriend doesn't really like to try new things,
所以我们一般吃得没什么新意
uh, so we pretty much just stick to the basics.
他不喜欢 不代表
Well, just 'cause he doesn't like something doesn't mean
你不能体验啊
you can't experience it.
杰西觉得墨西哥烤牛就挺有异域风情的了
Jesse thinks carne asada is exotic.
服了
Oh, my God.
–我得把你从 -嗯
-I'm gonna have to save you from, your, uh... -Hmm.
悲惨生活中拯救出来
your sad existence.
-我去 -用墨西哥辣椒薯片来拯救你
-Oh, my... -Jalape帽o chips to the rescue!
解放自我吧
Free yourself!
-开拓视野 -别闹了
-Expand your horizons! -Stop!
这个人有不少亲朋好友啊
This guy had a lot of people who loved him.
你家人会为你大办特办吗
Would your family do a whole dog and pony show for you?
不会
Uh... no.
他们能理解你对死亡的痴迷吗
They on board with your whole obsession with death?
希望能吧
I hope so.
他们都去世了
They're all dead.
-对不起 –没关系
-I'm sorry. -It's okay.
我挺喜欢聊起他们的
I like talking about them.
我爸 他是
My Dad-- he was, um...
他是个很棒的人
he was such a stud.
他带我们去锡安
He'd taken us to Zion
就因为他喜欢那些又大又笨重的石头
cause he liked these big, stupid rocks.
我妈可讨厌户外活动了 她很怕热
My mom hated the outdoors. She couldn't stand the heat,
讨厌虫子 但她爱我爸
the bugs, but she loved my dad.
萨迪就是爸爸的小棉袄
Sadie was a total Daddy's girl.
他去哪儿她都会跟上
She'd follow him anywhere.
查理
Charlie?
当时老爸正要讲个笑话
Dad was telling this dumb joke.
我要给你讲个笑话 准备好了没 小伙儿
I got a joke for you. You ready, bud?
他的笑话超老套的
CHARLIE: His jokes were so corny.
但那个笑话把我逗到了 是说
This one got me. Something about a...
一只猴子和一只鬣狗
a monkey and a hyena.
黑猩猩
Chimpanzee.
某种意义上来说 也算是恩赐
In a way, it was a blessing.
我没 没明白
I don't... I don't understand.
与死神擦肩而过
Having such a close brush with death
能看清楚很多事
brought everything into clear focus.
我看到生命的珍贵
I saw how precious life is.
作为活下来的人有责任
And how we as the living owe it to the dead
照顾逝者
to take care of them.
勇敢地生活
And to live boldly.
我完全理解你的感受
I know exactly how you feel.
也有个醉驾司机夺走了你全家的性命吗
Did some drunk driver take out your entire family
还是一场大火
as well in a blaze of glory?
创伤它...
Trauma is, uh...
是很复杂的
It's complicated.
它
It, um...
会影响你的心绪
It fucks with your... brain.
嘿 咱不是在聊我过世的家人么
Hey, I-I thought we were talking about my dead family.
我不会谈论我的家人 从没有过
I don't talk about mine, ever.
没跟杰西聊过 也没跟
Not with Jesse, not with, uh...
任何人聊起过
well, anyone.
但现在 我
But right now, I, um...
我想聊聊
I want to.
-嘿 -嘿 你在哪儿呢
-Hey. -Hey, where are you?
我尽量拖了 我爸妈都饿了
I've been stalling, my parents are getting hungry.
草 对不起
Shit. No. Uh, um, I'm sorry.
我忘干净了 我们
No. I totally spaced. We...
我们在准备葬礼
We're prepping for a service.
我现在就走 好吧
Um... I'm leaving now, okay?
我 十分钟后到家
I'll be... I'll be home in ten.
好吧 过会儿见
All right, see you soon.
嘿 我 我得走了
Hey, I... I got to go.
杰西的父母刚从辛辛那提飞过来
Um, Jesse's parents just flew in from Cincinnati.
-我忘干净这事儿了-没事
-I just totally spaced. -Don't worry about it.
我能搞定
I can finish up here.
谢谢
Thank you.
等等
Oh, wait.
你刚才想
You wanted to, uh,
跟我说些什么来着
tell me something.
我
I'll, um...
我以后再跟你说吧
I'll tell you later.
嗨 抱歉我回来晚了
Hi. Sorry I'm late.
旅途顺利吗
How was the flight?
不不不
No! No! No!
妈妈
Mama?
没事的 妈妈
It's okay, Mama.
没事的
-It's-it's okay.
没事的 没事的啊
-It's okay. It's okay.
没事的 怎么了
-It's okay. What is it?
你怎么了
What is it?
你总是囤一盒这种麦片
Uh, you always got a box of these stashed,
所以我以为这样会很浪漫
so I thought it'd be romantic.
让我俩单独谈谈
Give us a minute.
嘿 来抱抱
Hey, come here.
怎么回事 跟我说说
What is it? Talk to me.
是...是我的... 妈妈
It's, um... it's-it's my-my mom.
- 然后呢-她被杀了
-Yeah? -She was murdered.
一个男人闯进来猛砸她的头
A man broke in and bashed her head
厨房里到处都是血
and there was blood all over the kitchen, and...
-她最喜欢的就是这个了 -没关系
-these were her favorite. -It's all right. It's all right.
我总会留一盒
I always kept a box.
能让我觉得离她很近
It made me feel close to her.
你看
You see,
我完全搞砸了
I'm-I'm completely messed up.
你不会想娶我的
You don't-you don't want to marry me.
-我当然想娶你了 -你人真的太好了
-Of course I want to marry you. -Oh, well, you're so sweet, and
你该跟个很好 很善良 正常的女生在一起
you d-you deserve a nice, a nice, normal girl.
-我不配 -不不不不
-I'm not that person. -No, no, no, no, no.
-别这样 -我没法
-Don't do this. -I-I can't... I can't be
-成为你想我成为的那种女生 –别这么说 宝儿
-what you want me to be. -Don't do this. Honey.
-萨姆 别这样 -对不起
-Sam. Please. -No. I'm sorry.
嗨 约翰
Hi, John.
我是萨姆
I'm Sam.
今天由我来照顾你
I will be taking care of you today.
吸毒过量 26岁
OD. 26.
太年轻了
So young.
希望你这辈子过的值了
I hope you made the most of your time.
不
No...
该死 你太傻了
Goddamn it. You're so stupid.
你是唯一 一个
You were the only one.
唯— —个明白
The only one who understood what it was like
在黑暗的深渊中行走
to walk around with this...
是什么感觉的人
...this pit of darkness inside.
你在我身上看到了共鸣
You saw it in me.
而且也没有被吓到
And it didn't scare you.
所有人都会被我吓到
I scare everyone.
包括我自己
Even myself.
你让我觉得我不再孤单
You made me feel like I wasn't alone anymore.
天 我只是
God, I just...
我一个人太久了
I've been alone for so long.
查理
-Charlie!
Charlie!
萨姆
Sam?
你还活着
You're alive.
操
Fuck you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
听着 我搞砸了
Look, I screwed up.
-是我搞砸了-别碰我 好吧
-I screwed up. -Don't fucking touch me, okay?
-刚他妈是怎么回事 恶心的恶作剧吗 -不
-What the fuck was that, some sort of sick prank? -No.
本不该到那种地步的
It was never supposed to go that far.
我知道尸体该什么样
I know what a dead body looks like.
你他妈都不喘气了
You weren't fucking breathing.
这年头网上什么药都能找着
You can find a pill online for anything these days.
你胸口都被切开了
Your chest was cut open.
我都看见尸检疤痕了
I saw your fucking autopsy scar.
-我有个朋友很擅长修复术 –闭嘴 别
-I have a buddy who's good with prosthetics. -Just shut up! Just shut the...
别回嘴 好吗
Just shut the fuck up, okay?
我只是想帮你
I was trying to help you.
你他妈疯了
You're fucking deranged.
我他妈疯了 我他妈疯了
I'm fucking deranged? I'm fucking deranged?
听着
Listen.
你怎么说我都行
You can call me whatever you want.
但改变不了你上了我的事实
But it won't change the fact that you fucked me.
还有你喜欢我死尸的样子
And you liked that I was dead.
离我远点
Get the fuck off me.
你怕了
Okay, you're scared.
我也怕
I'm scared, too.
你还没明白吗
Don't you see?
萨姆 萨姆 没有正常可言
Sam, Sam, there's no normal,
我和你都正常不起来
there's no normal for me or you.
我们就是这种人
This is who we are.
我刚鬼迷心窍了好吧 你错了
No, that's not me, okay? You're wrong.
你他妈的 你他妈错了
You're fucking, you're fucking wrong.
我们新推出浓密防水睫毛膏
Our new volumizing waterproof mascara
就是个奇迹
is a miracle.
两个月后
在光照下很美 也可以随便哭
It goes on light, you can cry,
在雨中跳舞 尽情做
dance in the rain, go wild
水上增氧健身操 出水还是会幼菊一样清新可人
with your water aerobics and you'll stay fresh as a daisy.
不会有晕染 不会出现浣熊眼
No smudge, no raccoon eyes.
我看起来像是需要做水上增氧健身操的人吗
Do I look like I do water aerobics?
我们可以试着修饰下嘴唇
We can try a more subtle lip.
这个费贝奇女友色号可受欢迦了
Um, this Faberge Femme is a fan favorite.
-你们真的没必要这么做 -当然有必要了
-You guys really didn't have to do this. -Of course we did!
我们的小萨米要结婚了耶
Our little Sammy's getting married.
- 加油 杰西 上吧 -真不容易
-Go, Jesse, go! -Finally.
耶
-Yeah!
好了 谁准备好干杯了
All right, who's ready for shots?
-敬杰西- 谢谢
-To Jess. -Thank you, thank you,
谢谢 谢谢 谢谢
thank you, thank you, thank you...
-敬萨姆 -萨姆
-To Sammy. -Sammy!
结婚喽
Getting hitched!
我们正要去见婚礼策划人
We're meeting the wedding planner now.
我保证会提的 好吧
I promise I'll mention it, okay?
晚点打给你
Call you later.
-你没事吧 –没事 只是
-You okay? -Yeah, I'm just...
在幻想我们的婚礼
just daydreaming about our wedding.
-好吧 -你知道吗
-Oh. All right. -You know?
你看起来真美
You look so good.
操
Fuck.
我爱你 宝贝儿
I love you, babe.
我等不及想娶你进门了
I can't wait to make you my wife.
我也是
Me, too.
你看起来好美
You look beautiful.
我从没见过比你更悲伤的新娘
I have never seen a sadder bride.
你怎么了
What's going on with you?
我 没事
I'm... I'm fine.
只是 有些紧张
It's just... jitters.
自打你辞职后就一直怪怪的
You've been acting weird ever since you quit your job.
就像是蜥蜴人夺了你的身体
It's like the lizard people invaded your body,
现在你成了个喜欢蜡笔绘和下午茶的
and now you're this girl who likes pastels
女生
and afternoon tea.
我那个喜欢跟死人聊天
Where's my friend with the rocking hair
头发乱蓬蓬的朋女呢
who liked to talk to dead people?
这课不好笑
Okay, that's not funny.
我没开玩笑
I'm not joking.
你确定真想结婚吗
Are you sure you want to do this?
杰西是个好人 但是
Jesse's a great guy, but...
他能让你幸福吗
does he make you happy?
他当然让我幸福 我
Of course he makes me happy. I...
听着 这就是我想要的 我想
Look, this is, this is what I want. I want...
安稳度日 膝下有子
a white picket fence, 2.5 kids.
我只想过平淡 正常的生活
I just want a boring, regular life.
你向来对平淡正常的生活嗤之以鼻
You never gave a shit about a boring, regular life.
大家齐聚一堂 参加这位男士
OFFICIANT: We are gathered here today to join this man
以及这位女士的神圣婚礼
and this woman in holy matrimony.
杰西和萨曼莎
Jesse and Samantha
经各自准备好誓言
have prepared their own vows
来表达他们的爱
to express their love.
萨曼莎
Samantha?
谢谢
Thank you.
杰西
Jesse.
从小到大
Growing up, I...
我几乎没有家人
didn't really have a family.
本来觉得无所谓的 我
And that was okay. I...
学会了过没有家人的生活
learned to get through life without one.
但后来我遇到了你
But then I met you.
我只
You are...
需要你
(sniffles) ...all I need.
萨姆
Sam...
我第一次看到你
the first time I saw you...
穿着那件大T恤
in that Garbage T-shirt,
狂灌着时代啤酒时
-throwing back a Stella...
我就想 我要娶这姑娘
I thought, I'm gonna marry that girl.
你就是我的唯一
You are the only one for me.
多年后
And years from now,
等我们身边围着我们的孩子
when we're surrounded by our kids
和孙辈
and our grandkids,
我们就会跟他们讲今天的事
we'll tell them about this day.
给他们讲
And show them
我们的故事
our story.
这不是仪式的一部分
This wasn't part of the program.
有时候打破常规也挺有意思的
Sometimes it can be fun to go off script.
他们好有爱
They're so cute.
那是萨姆吗
Is that Sam?
那是具尸体吗
POPPY: Is that a dead body?
-那是什么 -杰西 你 你
-What is that? -Jesse, you, uh, you...
-拜托你告诉我那不是你 -杰西 你 你不 你不懂
-Please tell me that's not you. -Jesse, you-you don't, you don't understand...
他永远都不会理解你的 萨姆
He's never gonna understand you, Sam.
看看他都做了什么
Look at what he's done.
-抹杀了你身上的所有特别之处 -他是谁啊
-Killed everything special about you. -Who the fuck is he?
他 我们一起工作过
SAM: He, we-we used to work together...
那是视频里那个人
That's the guy in the video.
所以那不是具尸体吗
So it's not a dead body?
不 不 很明显他没死
No, no, he's not dead, obviously.
你听我说 这只是个有点过分的玩笑
Look, this is, it's a sick joke.
-仅此而已 -嗯 但是你确实以为我死了
-This is all... -Yeah, but you thought I was dead.
我觉得这给了你许可
And I think that gave you permission.
让你能做你真正的自己 去追求
The green light to be who you really are, to want what you
-你真正想要的东西 和我在一起 -他 他是出现幻觉了
-really want, to be with me. -He's-he's delusional.
都录下来了 萨姆
There's a tape, Sam!
你趴在一具尸体上
That's you climbing on top of a corpse.
不管是死人还是活人 你都是在上别人
Dead or not, that's you fucking another guy.
-你是谁 -听着
-Who are you? - Look,
我是被骗了 这整件事 这
I-I was tricked. This whole thing, it's a cr--
-这就是个天大的误会 -去你的 萨姆
-it's a crazy misunderstanding. -Fuck you, Sam.
杰西
-Jesse!
杰西 对不起
Jesse, I'm sorry!
杰西停下 杰西
Jesse, stop. Jesse!
–萨姆 萨姆 萨姆 停下 快停下 -你放手 什么
-Sam, Sam, Sam! Stop, stop! -Let fucking go of me! What?
-你还拍了视频是吗 -这就是真正
-You fucking filmed us? -That is what it looks like
活着的样子
to really be alive.
只有这样我才能救你
This was the only way I could save you.
因为我爱你
Because I love you.
我知道你也爱我
And I know you feel the same.
不 我不爱 我恨死你了
No, I don't. I fucking hate you.
你滚远点
Leave me the hell alone.
看起来你有很丰富的
Well, I can see you have a lot
废物处理经验
of experience in waste disposal.
是的 我处理过
Yes, uh, I've handled every type
你能想到的各种污物
of mess you can imagine.
呕吐物的话 次氯酸钠
Um, for vomit, sodium hypochlorite
和猫砂最有用了
and kitty litter works best.
地板沾上血迹的话 诀窍是
For blood stains on the carpet, the trick is
撒点土豆淀粉
sprinkle a little potato starch actually.
大多数人都不知道怎么清洗马桶
Most people don't even know how to disinfect a toilet.
很简单 用醋就行
Oh, that's easy, vinegar.
很显然你能胜任这份工作
Clearly, you can do the work.
你很擅长清理烂摊了
You know your way around a dirty mess.
抱歉 麻烦
Sorry, excuse me
-等我一下 -嗯
-one minute. -Yeah.
我 很抱歉
I, uh, apologize.
看来我们已经招到人了
It seems like we just filled the position.
要是有机会的活
Oh, um, well, if anything opens up,
我很乐意清理那些没人愿意碰的活儿
I'm happy to take the job nobody wants.
我工作很努力
I'm a very hard worker and, um...
女士
Miss...
我们不能让一个性侵犯
we can't have a sex offender
进客户的家
going into our clients' homes.
不 我 我不是
No, I'm-I'm not, um...
听者 我犯了—个错
Look, I made one mistake.
你这辈子就没犯过错吗
Haven't you ever made a mistake in your life?
我每天都在为此付出代价 求你了
I'm paying for it every single day, please.
我真的急用钱
I-I could really use the cash.
你能给我个机会吗
Can you just give me a chance? Um...
操僵尸的
Zombie fucker!
你毁了我的生活
You ruined my life.
萨姆
Sam...
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
我知道你生我的气
I get you're angry with me.
闭嘴
Shut up.
我的朋友们不理我了
My friends won't talk to me anymore.
没人会雇佣我 因为
No one will hire me 'cause everyone thinks
他们都觉得我是个性侵犯 但是明明
I'm a fucking sex offender, when you're
撒谎的人是你
the one who lied.
是你骗了我
You tricked me.
你夺走了
You took...
我的一切
everything.
现在你还指望好好过你的生活
And now you get to just keep living your best life?
这可不行
Hmm, it's just not right.
你需要为你做过的事付出代价
You need to pay for what you've done.
萨姆 对不起
Sam, I'm sorry.
求你了
Please.
我们理智地谈谈吧
We can talk rationally.
你不是这样的人
This is not who you are.
我想要答案
-I just want some answers.
我就想知道为什么 我是做了什么伤天害理的事
I just want to know why. What, what did I do to deserve this?
你要这么恨我
Why do you hate me so fucking much?
你这笨蛋 我不恨你
You idiot, I don't hate you!
你被困住了 我只想放你自由
You were trapped! I was trying to set you free!
我不需要帮助
I didn't want any help!
我没求你帮我 我过得挺好的
I never asked for it. I was fine.
不 你不好
No, you weren't!
操了 萨姆
Fuck, Sam.
我的家人死的那天
The day my family died...
我离死亡如此之近 我都能尝到死亡的味道
I was so close to death, I tasted it.
我身上全是他们的血
I had their blood on me.
而我
And I...
真正觉得我活看
felt so alive.
我第一次真正醒来了
I was waking up for the first time.
看清了这世界本来的面目
Seeing the world how it really was.
不要再假装岁月静好了
No more pretending everything's fine
因为这世界根本就不好
when the world's not fucking fine.
我以为如果我能让你
I thought if I could give you that,
与死亡擦肩而过
a close brush with death,
你也会醒来
it would shock you awake.
本来几分钟就好的
It was only supposed to be for a few minutes.
就是想推动你
Just a jump start.
但是你哭了
But then you were crying.
然后开始抚摸我
And you touched me.
而我
And I...
不想让你停下来
I didn't want it to stop.
我不想打破那个瞬间
I didn't want to break the spell.
我对其他人从来没有过
I have never felt that way before
那种感觉
with anyone.
你疯了吧
You're psychotic.
我不需要男人来告诉我
I don't need a man to tell me
我该怎么想该怎么做
what I think or what I really want.
你太自以为是了
That is so goddamn patronizing.
我知道你妈的事
And I know about your mother.
我发誓 你再多说
I swear to God, if you say one fucking...
三天
Three days.
她已经死了三天
She was dead for three days
别人才找到你
before they found you.
三天里 你喝了你死去母亲的母乳
For three days, you drank your dead mother's milk.
你闭嘴
Shut the fuck up.
你真恶心
You're disgusting.
你也很恶心
但很美
And beautiful.
又破碎
And fucked up.
又美好
And amazing.
你什么样子都有
You are all those things, all at the same time.
所以这就是为什么我爱你
And that's why I love you.
我爱你 萨姆
I love you, Sam.
你不用再躲藏了
You don't have to hide anymore.
让我看到真正的你 告诉我
Let the real you out, and tell me,
第―次品尝死亡是什么感觉
what did it feel like, to taste death for the first time?
感觉像爱
It felt like love.
一开始我以为她
At first, I thought she had just...
只是撞到了头
bumped her head.
然后睡着了
And she was sleeping.
我梳了她的头发
I brushed her hair.
我
I...
我给她吃麦片
I fed her cereal.
就我和妈妈两个人
Just Mama and me.
那是我最后一次有安全感
It was the last time I ever felt safe.
怪不得我这么奇怪 操
No wonder I'm so screwed up, fuck.
然后我
And I...
我以为我再也不会有那种感觉了
I thought I would never feel like that again.
直到那天晚上
Until that night.
和你在一起
Until I was with you.
变态吧
How fucked up is that?
我明白
I get it.
我理解你
I get you.
我永远不会评判你
I will never judge you.
你应该让我继续浑浑噩噩下去的
You should've just let me keep sleepwalking.
我都忘了我有多破碎
I had forgotten I was broken.
但是现在我看出来了
But now I see.
我真正想要的是同时
I think what I really want is to be dead
活着并死去
and alive at the same time.
这永远不可能
And I can never have that.
我永远拼不好碎掉的碎片
There's no way to put the pieces back together.
我已经没救了
There's no hope for me.
萨姆
Sam.
我们在一起就有希望
There's hope for us.
为了和你在一起
I would do anything...
我什么都愿意做
to be with you.
我愿意死一百万次
I would die a million times
来换和你在一起的一分钟
to be with you for a minute.
一千年
For a thousand years.
永远
Forever.
你是认真的 对吧
You really mean that, don't you?
你很奇怪 我很奇怪
Your weird and my weird,
我们就应该在一起
we belong together.
我们可以过得很快乐
We can be happy.
我们可以过得很快乐吗
We can be happy?
让我给你幸福
Let me make you happy.
嗯
Yeah.
我觉得只有你可以
I think you're the only one that could.
一分钟
For a minute.
一千年
For a thousand years.
永远
Forever.